{
  "q1": [
    {
      "question": "A work by this man inspired al-Farabi’s [ahl fuh-RAH-bee’s] book The Virtuous City. In one\nof this man’s works, the title character offers to break his friend out of prison, but is stopped by\nthat friend's insistence on following the law. One of this man's works presents four “affections”\nof the psyche using the Analogy of the Divided Line. In that work, this man conceived of a\nperfect state ruled by philosopher-kings. For 10 points, name this author of the Crito and\nRepublic, two of his namesake dialogues.",
      "answer": [
        "Plato",
        "Platon"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "A name used to describe these objects was first coined by the English philosopher Thomas Wright and was later used by Kant to describe so-called “nebulous objects” in the heavens. The “Great Debate” concerning the distance to these objects pitted Harlow Shapley against Heber Curtis. The distance to these “island universes” was calculated through observations by Hubble. For 10 points, name these giant groups of stars, examples of which include the Milky Way.",
      "answer": "galaxies"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man wrote an analysis of the German psyche after World War II titled Anti-Semite and Jew. This first editor of the journal Modern Times popularized the phrase “existence precedes essence” in his Existentialism and Humanism, which rejected deterministic excuses for behavior. This philosopher popularized the idea that there are “two modes of consciousness,” and that “bad faith” forces human beings to adopt false values, in his Being and Nothingness. For ten points, name this French post-war philosopher and Nobel Laureate who was married to Simone de Beauvoir.",
      "answer": "Jean-Paul Sartre"
    },
    {
      "question": "This man’s philosophy notably clashed with that of his contemporary, Antoine-Henri Jomini. One of this thinker’s students applied his philosophy at the Battle of Sedan; that student was Helmuth von Moltke. This man defined war as “the continuation of politics by other means,” and he described the confusion during “the fog of war” in his most famous work. For ten points, name this distinguished 19th century Prussian military strategist who wrote On War.",
      "answer": "Carl von Clausewitz"
    },
    {
      "question": "This philosopher originated the image of a “tree falling in a forest” with nobody around to hear it as part of an argument that God must exist to percieve the whole universe at all times. That image, which later reappeared in a limerick, comes from this thinker’s Treatise Concerning the Principles of Human Knowledge. This thinker later wrote that “to be is to be perceived” in Three Dialogues Between Hylas and Philonous. For ten points, name this “immaterialist” Anglo-Irish philosopher who lends his name to a university city in California.",
      "answer": "Bishop George Berkeley , but be lenient"
    },
    {
      "question": "During a visit to this country, one psychologist stated that his only goal was to “catch sight of a porcupine;” that trip led Sigmund Freud to conclude that this country “was a mistake.” A psychologist from this country developed the ideas of habit, will, and stream of consciousness in his book Principles of Psychology; that man also wrote the book Pragmatism. For ten points, name this home country of William James, who was a professor at Harvard.",
      "answer": [
        "United States of America or USA",
        "America"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "This philosopher, who developed a method of steam distillation to produce rose water and essential oils, claimed he had read Aristotle’s Metaphysics 40 times before reading a commentary by al-Farabi. This main target of al-Ghazali’s The Incoherence of the Philosophers argued for the existence of the soul with the “floating man” argument. The Canon of Medicine and The Book of Healing were written by, for ten points, what Persian Islamic philosopher of the 11th century?",
      "answer": [
        "Avicenna or ibn Sina",
        "or Abu Ali Sina",
        "or Pur Sina"
      ]
    },
    {
      "question": "Due to his money struggles, this philosopher was offered fifty years pay in advance by Catherine the Great to serve as her personal librarian. Pope Clement XIII [[the Thirteenth]] banned a compendium written by this man, citing its skepticism of Jesus' miracles. Alongside Jean d'Alembert [[dahl-ehm-BARE]], this man compiled a \"systematic dictionary of the sciences, arts, and crafts.\" The chief editor of the Encyclopédie [[ohn-see-cloh-PEH-dee]] was, for ten points, which French philosopher?",
      "answer": "Denis Diderot ]"
    }
  ],
  "q2": [
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "While working on his Ph.D. in this city, Frederic Thrasher undertook a comprehensive study of 1,313 of its gangs. Sudhir Venkatesh’s Gang Leader for a Day relied on field research in this city, where Venkatesh also collected data on prostitutes that was presented in a 2005 book. That work, Freakonomics, was co-written by Steven Levitt, an economics professor who works in this city. Twelve Nobel Prizes in Economics have been awarded to professors like Milton Friedman who teach in, for ten points, what Midwestern city?",
        "answer": "Chicago"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "The Chicago school of economics generally rejects the theories of this British economist, who advocated deficit spending to spur economies out of recessions.",
        "answer": [
          "John Maynard Keynes , but be lenient",
          "Keynesian economics"
        ]
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "In one work by this philosopher, the drunken Alcibiades bursts in after various luminaries take turns giving speeches about love. This thinker postulated the existence of abstract forms, such as the Good. Another work by this founder of the Academy envisions an ideal city-state and includes the Allegory of the Cave. For ten points, name this author of the Symposium and the Republic, a Greek philosopher who wrote many dialogues featuring his teacher Socrates.",
        "answer": "Plato"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Platonic dialogue is the origin of the problem of whether “the pious” is loved by the gods becauseitisgood,orifitisgoodbecauseitislovedbythegods;thatisthiswork’seponymous“dilemma.”",
        "answer": "Euthyphro , but be lenient"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "This thinker contrasted the use of windmills in pre-industrial Europe with power plants along the Rhine River in his The Question Concerning Technology. This thinker, who discussed the essence of art in The Origin of the Work of Art, was labeled a Mitl¨aufer [MITT-loy-fer] following World War II. For ten points, name this German philosopher who defined dasein in the book Being and Time and was a prominent member of the Nazi Party.",
        "answer": "Martin Heidegger"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Despite his Nazi membership, Heidegger had an affair with this Jewish German-American philosopher. This philosopher wrote historical philosophy books like Eichmann in Jerusalem and The Origins of Totalitarianism.",
        "answer": "Hannah Arendt"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Leo Strauss argued that this man was the first modern thinker in his Thoughts on this philosopher. An essay by Frederick the Great rebuts this philosopher, who praised Cesare Borgia as the ideal ruler. This philosopher’s major work of political philosophy was dedicated to his patron, Lorenzo de Medici, and argued that it is better to be feared than loved. For ten points, name this Italian renaissance philosopher who wrote The Prince.",
        "answer": "Niccolo Machiavelli"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Machiavelli also wrote a series of Discourses on this Roman historian, who wrote the now mostly lost Ab Urbe Condita.",
        "answer": "Titus Livius or Livy"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "One work dictated by this man was partially lost by his neighbor, Martin Harris, and was allegedly verified in the presence of the Three Witnesses. Religious communities established by this man included those in Kirtland and Independence. This man was murdered by a mob after he ordered the destruction of a printing press for the Expositor. This man claimed to have been given two golden plates containing sacred texts by the angel Moroni. For ten points, name this founder of the Mormon Church.",
        "answer": "Joseph Smith, Jr."
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "Smith was murdered while in a jail cell in this state's city of Carthage. Smith had also gained control of the government of this state's nearby city of Nauvoo.",
        "answer": "Illinois"
      }
    },
    {
      "tossup": {
        "question": "Antonio Gramsci referred to this philosophy as the \"philosophy of praxis\" in his Prison Notebooks while imprisoned by Italy's Fascist regime. With Arnold Ruge [[ROO-guh]], this philosophy's namesake led the newspaper the German-French Annals. Lesser known books by this philosophy's namesake include Grundrisse and The German Ideology. Espoused by the Maoist and Bolshevik parties, for ten points, what is this communist philosophy named after the author of Das Kapital?",
        "answer": "Marxism"
      },
      "bonus": {
        "question": "This Marxist philosopher outlined his namesake philosophy in books such as The State and Revolution and Imperialism: the Highest Stage of Capitalism. This revolutionary also issued ten directives in his \"April Theses.\"",
        "answer": [
          "Vladimir Ilyich Lenin",
          "Vladimire Ilyich Ulyanov"
        ]
      }
    }
  ],
  "q3": [],
  "q4": [
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) One philosopher at this school criticized the collectivist foundations of a colleague’s work in his Liberalism and the Limits of Justice. That philosopher, Michael Sandel, teaches a popular introductory course on “Justice” at this university. Another philosopher affiliated with this university allowed for large inequalities if they were a result of free exchange in his (20 pts)",
        "Anarchy, State, and Utopia; that philosopher was Robert Nozick. Both of those works were written in response to another author from this university, who developed the idea of the (10 pts)",
        "“veil of ignorance” in his A Theory of Justice. For ten points, name this Ivy League school where John Rawls taught."
      ],
      "answer": "Harvard University"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This philosopher’s idea that a human being consists merely of its properties and nothing intrinsically substantive is known as his “bundle theory.” This philosopher stirred up controversy by praising polytheism and suggesting it led to monotheistic religions in his (20 pts)",
        "Natural History of Religion. A law named after this man states that thinkers commit a fallacy when they move from positive to normative statements and is called his (10 pts)",
        "“is-ought problem.” For ten points, name this Scottish philosopher who wrote An Enquiry Concerning Human Understanding."
      ],
      "answer": "David Hume"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) This philosopher argued that, since a point is a place in space that takes up no space, it is best defined as “a negation of itself.” Karl Popper argued that the political philosophy of this one-time roommate of Schelling and Holderlin was a thinly veiled defense of (20 pts)",
        "Frederick William III. A philosophical circle which included Max Stirner were the so called “Young” followers of this thinker, in whose system a (10 pts)",
        "“thesis” and “antithesis” sublate into a “synthesis.” For ten points, name this philosopher who espoused his dialectical system in The Science of Logic and The Phenomenology of Spirit."
      ],
      "answer": "Georg Wilhelm Friedrich Hegel"
    },
    {
      "parts": [
        "(30 pts) Scholars argue that an Arabic expansion of Diophantus’ Arithmetica was actually written by this thinker, citing an idiosyncratic method for dividing in base 60. After strife between the prefect Orestes and the patriarch (20 pts)",
        "Cyril broke out, this thinker was labeled a heretic and murdered by a Christian mob in 415 AD in (10 pts)",
        "her hometown of Alexandria, making her a martyr for future philosophers. Ptolemy’s Almagest was edited by, for ten points, what Neoplatonist philosopher and mathematician?"
      ],
      "answer": "Hypatia of Alexandria"
    }
  ]
}